Paul Baker papers, Inclusive:1953-1959, Bulk: 1957-1958
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Paul Baker papers
Inclusive:1953-1959, Bulk: 1957-1958
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3869
Bryant, C. E.
1 document box
The Paul Baker papers contain biographical materials about the life and professional career of Paul Baker, a famous theater director and chair of the Baylor Theatre Department from 1940 until 1963.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
C. E. Bryant (1917-2000) was born in Booneville, Arkansas, as Cyril Eric Bryant Jr. in 1918. Ordained at age 18 by his home church, he attended Ouachita College (now Ouachita University) for two years. Bryant transferred to Baylor University to study journalism under longtime professor Frank Burkhalter. Graduating in 1939, Bryant became director of Baylor's Public Relations Office. With the onset of World War II, Bryant moved on to jobs at Ridgecrest Baptist Assembly in North Carolina, Southern Baptist Theological Seminary in Kentucky, and the Arkansas Baptist Newsmagazine. In 1947, he joined the team at Baptist Press. Bryant returned to Baylor in 1949 as the director of public relations, serving in that role until 1957. The final job of his professional career was as the first director of communications at the Baptist World Alliance, 1957-1982. C.E. Bryant passed away in 2000 and is buried in Lake View Memorial Gardens, St. Clair County, Illinois.
Scope and Content
The Paul Baker papers were created when C. E. Bryant undertook writing a biographical story about Paul Baker for publishing in the popular magazine Reader's Digest. As such, the collection contains correspondence between Bryant and Baker describing the project and mentioning biographical details about Baker's life, drafts of the biographical sketch, and programs and other things relating to Baker's plays and productions while at Baylor. There are also letters from Baker's students describing teaching methods, stories from the classroom, and other firsthand accounts of Baker's influence on students' lives and careers.
Arrangement
The Paul Baker papers were arranged in folders with titles. Original order of the folders and the items within each folder were maintained.
Currently, the Paul Baker papers are arranged in two series: I. Correspondence and II. Literary Productions.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3869.
Related Resources
Related references
Find A Grave, Inc. "Cyril E. Bryant." Databases. Memorial #94677666. Accessed on 2021 March 26.
Toalston, Art. "C.E. Bryant, first Baptist Press director & communications pioneer, dies at 82." Baptist Press, 2000 January 10. Accessed 2021 March 26.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Baker, Paul, 1911-2009.
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University Theater Arts Department.
Subjects
Theater -- Study and teaching.; Theater management.
Genres
Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Theater programs.
- Correspondence, 1956-1959; 1
  Administrative Information
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains letters between Bryant and various people, including former students of Paul Baker, and Baker himself. Most letters contain biographical information about Paul Baker or have information about Baker's life. This series is in good condition.
  - Letters, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters (1 of 2), 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters (1 of 2), 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Literary Productions, 1953-circa 1958; 2
  This series contains materials about Baker's theater productions, a commencement address he gave at Trinity University, and several different drafts of a Reader's Digest article written about him by C.E. Bryant. This series is in average condition.
  - Clippings, 1953-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Programs, circa 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notes, circa 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - News Releases, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Commencement Address, Trinity University, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Readers Digest biography, drafts (1 of 2), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Readers Digest biography, drafts (2 of 2), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Readers Digest biography, drafts (1 of 2), 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Readers Digest biography, drafts (2 of 2), 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)